<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSF on Agnès Pérez-Millan</title>
    <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/csf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CSF on Agnès Pérez-Millan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/csf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond group classification: Probabilistic differential diagnosis of frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer’s disease with MRI and CSF biomarkers</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>Agnès Pérez-Millan, Bertrand Thirion, Neus Falgàs, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Beatriz Bosch, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Adrià Tort-Merino, Jordi Sarto, Josep Maria Augé, Anna Antonell, Nuria Bargalló, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sánchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch. Neurobiology of Aging.
ABSTRACT
Neuroimaging and fluid biomarkers are used to differentiate frontotemporal dementia (FTD) from Alzheimer’s disease (AD). We implemented a machine learning algorithm that provides individual probabilistic scores based on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locus coeruleus integrity and neuropsychiatric symptoms in a cohort of early-and late-onset Alzheimer’s disease</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-locus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-locus/</guid>
      <description>Neus Falgàs, Marta Peña-González, Andrea Val-Guardiola, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Núria Guillén, Jordi Sarto, Diana Esteller, Beatriz Bosch, Guadalupe Fernández-Villullas, Adrià Tort-Merino, Gerard Mayà, Josep Maria Augé, Alex Iranzo, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Manuel Morales-Ruiz, Núria Bargalló, Emma Muñoz-Moreno, Lea T Grinberg, Raquel Sánchez-Valle. Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; Dementia.
ABSTRACT
INTRODUCTION Early-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (EOAD) shows a higher burden of neuropsychiatric symptoms than late-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (LOAD). We aim to determine the differences in the severity of neuropsychiatric symptoms and locus coeruleus (LC) integrity between EOAD and LOAD accounting for disease stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive profile, neuroimaging and fluid biomarkers in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-covid/</guid>
      <description>Núria Guillén*, Agnès Pérez-Millan*, Neus Falgàs, Gema M Lledó-Ibáñez, Lorena Rami, Jordi Sarto, Maria A Botí, Cristina Arnaldos-Pérez, Raquel Ruiz-García, Laura Naranjo, Bàrbara Segura, Mircea Balasa, Roser Sala-Llonch, Albert Lladó, Sarah M Gray, Jason K Johannesen, Madeline M Pantoni, Grant A Rutledge, Ruta Sawant, Yi Wang, Luke S Watson, Josep Dalmau, Raquel Sánchez‐Valle. (* equivalent contribution). Scientific Reports.
ABSTRACT
We aimed to characterize the cognitive profile of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PACS) patients with cognitive complaints, exploring the influence of biological and psychological factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XXVIII Reunió Anual Societat Catalana de Neurologia</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-catalana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-catalana/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Neus Falgàs, Beatriz Bosch, Uma Maria Lal-Trehan Estrada, Núria Guillén, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sánchez-Valle
TITLE: Asimetria cortical en individus en risc de patir malaltia d&amp;rsquo;Alzheimer
CONFERENCE: XXVIII Reunió Anual Societat Catalana de Neurologia
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: May 8 - 10, 2024</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Down Syndrome associated Alzheimer disease (DSAD) and autosomal dominant AD (ADAD)</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-adad-rsv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-adad-rsv/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Neus Falgàs, Beatriz Bosch, Uma Maria Lal-Trehan Estrada, Núria Guillén, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sánchez-Valle
TITLE: Cortical Asymmetry in individuals with Autosomal Dominant Alzheimer’s Disease
CONFERENCE: Down Syndrome associated Alzheimer disease (DSAD) and autosomal dominant AD (ADAD)
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: April 11 - 12, 2024</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Down Syndrome associated Alzheimer disease (DSAD) and autosomal dominant AD (ADAD)</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-adad-apm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-adad-apm/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Anna Antonell, Beatriz Bosch, Neus Falgàs, Núria Guillén, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Laura Molina-Porcel, Albert Lladó, Mircea Balasa, Antonio Boza-Serrano, Raquel Sánchez-Valle
TITLE: Galectin-3 is upregulated and correlated with MRI findings in Autosomal Dominant Alzheimer’s Disease and Genetic Frontotemporal Dementia
CONFERENCE: Down Syndrome associated Alzheimer disease (DSAD) and autosomal dominant AD (ADAD)
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: April 11 - 12, 2024</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of demographics and comorbid conditions on plasma biomarkers concentrations and their diagnostic accuracy in a memory clinic cohort</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-plasma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-plasma/</guid>
      <description>Jordi Sarto, Diana Esteller-Gauxax, Adrià Tort-Merino, Núria Guillén, Agnès Pérez‐Millan, Neus Falgàs, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Guadalupe Fernández-Villullas, Beatriz Bosch, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Anna Antonell, Laura Naranjo, Raquel Ruiz-García, Josep María Augé, Raquel Sánchez-Valle, Albert Lladó, Mircea Balasa. Journal of Neurology.
ABSTRACT
Plasma biomarkers have emerged as promising tools for identifying amyloid beta (Aβ) pathology. Before implementation in routine clinical practice, confounding factors modifying their concentration beyond neurodegenerative diseases should be identified. We studied the association of a comprehensive list of demographics, comorbidities, medication and laboratory parameters with plasma p-tau181, glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) and neurofilament light chain (NfL) on a prospective memory clinic cohort and studied their impact on diagnostic accuracy for discriminating CSF/amyloid PET-defined Aβ status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cortical thickness modeling and variability in Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal dementia</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-cth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-cth/</guid>
      <description>Agnès Pérez‐Millan, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Neus Falgàs, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Beatriz Bosch, Adrià Tort-Merino, Anna Antonell, Nuria Bargalló, Lorena Rami, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sánchez-Valle. Journal of Neurology.
ABSTRACT
Background and objective Alzheimer’s disease (AD) and frontotemporal dementia (FTD) show different patterns of cortical thickness (CTh) loss compared with healthy controls (HC), even though there is relevant heterogeneity between individuals suffering from each of these diseases. Thus, we developed CTh models to study individual variability in AD, FTD, and HC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galectin-3 is upregulated in frontotemporal dementia patients with subtype specificity</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-gal3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-gal3/</guid>
      <description>Sergi Borrego-Écija*, Agnès Pérez-Millan*, Anna Antonell, Laura Fort-Aznar, Elif Kaya-Tilki, Alberto León-Halcón, Albert Lladó, Laura Molina-Porcel, Mircea Balasa, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Javier Vitorica, Jose Luis Venero, Tomas Deierborg, Antonio Boza-Serrano, Raquel Sánchez-Valle. (* equivalent contribution). Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; Dementia.
ABSTRACT
INTRODUCTION Neuroinflammation is a major contributor to the progression of frontotemporal dementia (FTD). Galectin-3 (Gal-3), a microglial activation regulator, holds promise as a therapeutic target and potential biomarker. Our study aimed to investigate Gal-3 levels in patients with FTD and assess its diagnostic potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VII Jornadas científicas de estudiantes de la SEB</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-biostatistica/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-biostatistica/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Uma Maria Lal-Trehan Estrada, Neus Falgàs, Núria Guillén, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Beatriz Bosch, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Adrià Tort-Merino, Jordi Sarto, Josep Maria Augé, Anna Antonell, Núria Bargalló, Raquel Ruiz-García, Laura Naranjo, Mireca Balasa, Albert Lladó, Roser Sala Llonch, Raquel Sánchez-Valle
TITLE: The Cortical Asymmetry Index (CAI) for subtyping frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease patients
CONFERENCE: VII Jornadas científicas de estudiantes de la SEB
PLACE: Varcelona, Spain
DATES: February 7 - 9, 2024</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OHBM 2023 ANNUAL MEETING</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-ohbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-ohbm/</guid>
      <description>MERIT POSTER AWARD
AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Bertrand Thirion, Sergi Borrego‐Écija, José Contador, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Beatriz Bosch, Neus Falgàs, Anna Antonell, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch.
TITLE: Probabilistic classification of Alzheimer’s Disease and Frontotemporal Dementia.
CONFERENCE: OHBM 2023 ANNUAL MEETING
PLACE: Montréal, Canada
DATES: July 22 - 26, 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAIC 2023</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaiccovid-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaiccovid-ng/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Núria Guillén, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Neus Falgàs, María Ángeles Botí, Adrià Tort-Merino, Gema María Lledó-Ibáñez, Raquel Ruiz-García, Laura Naranjo, Lorena Rami, Mircea Balasa, Roser Sala-Llonch, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle.
TITLE: Cognitive symptoms associated with COVID-19: neuropsychological and biochemical characterization.
CONFERENCE: Alzheimer’s Association International Conference (AAIC) 2023
PLACE: Amsterdam, Netherlands
DATES: July 16 - 20, 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAIC 2023</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaicml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaicml/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Bertrand Thirion, Sergi Borrego‐Écija, José Contador, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Beatriz Bosch, Neus Falgàs, Anna Antonell, Raquel Ruiz-García, Laura Naranjo, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó,Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sanchez-Valle.
TITLE: Probabilistic computer-aided diagnosis of Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal dementia based on MRI and biochemical markers.
CONFERENCE: Alzheimer’s Association International Conference (AAIC) 2023
PLACE: Amsterdam, Netherlands
DATES: July 16 - 20, 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAIC 2023</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaicsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaicsb/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Sergi Borrego Écija, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Raquel Ruiz-García, Jordi Sarto, Neus Falgàs, Diana Esteller, Núria Guillén, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Guadalupe Fernández, Yolanda González, Adrià Tort-Merino, Bea Bosch, Laura Fort-Aznar, Anna Antonell, Laura Naranjo, Albert Lladó, Mircea Balasa, Raquel Sanchez-Valle.
TITLE: Plasma Nfl predicts neuroimaging alterations and functional decline in frontotemporal dementia.
CONFERENCE: Alzheimer’s Association International Conference (AAIC) 2023
PLACE: Amsterdam, Netherlands
DATES: July 16 - 20, 2023</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
