<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AD on Agnès Pérez-Millan</title>
    <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/ad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AD on Agnès Pérez-Millan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/ad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sex differences in early-onset Alzheimer’s disease</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-sex/</guid>
      <description>ABSTRACT
INTRODUCTION: Sex is believed to drive heterogeneity in Alzheimer’s disease (AD), although evidence in early-onset AD (&amp;lt;65 years, EOAD) is scarce.
METHODS: We included 62 EOAD patients and 44 healthy controls (HC) with cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) AD’s core biomarkers and neurofilament light chain levels, neuropsychological assessment, and 3T-MRI. We measured cortical thickness (CTh) and hippocampal subfield volumes (HpS) using Freesurfer. Adjusted linear models were used to analyze sex-differences and the relationship between atrophy and cognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the performance of Bayesian and frequentist approaches for longitudinal modeling: application to Alzheimer’s disease</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-bayvsfreq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-bayvsfreq/</guid>
      <description>ABSTRACT
Linear mixed effects (LME) modelling under both frequentist and Bayesian frameworks can be used to study longitudinal trajectories. We studied the performance of both frameworks on different dataset configurations using hippocampal volumes from longitudinal MRI data across groups—healthy controls (HC), mild cognitive impairment (MCI) and Alzheimer’s disease (AD) patients, including subjects that converted from MCI to AD. We started from a big database of 1250 subjects from the Alzheimer’s disease neuroimaging initiative (ADNI), and we created different reduced datasets simulating real-life situations using a random-removal permutation-based approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
