<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FTD on Agnès Pérez-Millan</title>
    <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/ftd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FTD on Agnès Pérez-Millan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/ftd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal dementia using machine learning with cross‐sectional and longitudinal magnetic resonance imaging data</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2023-mllong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2023-mllong/</guid>
      <description>Agnès Pérez‐Millan, José Contador, Jordi Juncà‐Parella, Beatriz Bosch, Laia Borrell, Adrià Tort‐Merino, Neus Falgàs, Sergi Borrego‐Écija, Nuria Bargalló, Lorena Rami, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sánchez‐Valle, Roser Sala‐Llonch. Human Brain Mapping.
ABSTRACT
Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) and frontotemporal dementia (FTD) are common causes of dementia with partly overlapping, symptoms and brain signatures. There is a need to establish an accurate diagnosis and to obtain markers for disease tracking. We combined unsupervised and supervised machine learning to discriminate between AD and FTD using brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of brainstem white matter predicts onset and motor neuron symptoms in C9orf72 expansion carriers: a GENFI study</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-c9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-c9/</guid>
      <description>Agnès Pérez-Millan*, Sergi Borrego-Écija*, John C van Swieten, Lize Jiskoot, Fermin Moreno, Robert Laforce, Caroline Graff, Mario Masellis, Maria Carmela Tartaglia, James B Rowe, Barbara Borroni, Elizabeth Finger, Matthis Synofzik, Daniela Galimberti, Rik Vandenberghe, Alexandre de Mendonça, Chris R Butler, Alexander Gerhard, Simon Ducharme, Isabelle Le Ber, Isabel Santana, Florence Pasquier, Johannes Levin, Markus Otto, Sandro Sorbi, Pietro Tiraboschi, Harro Seelaar, Tobias Langheinrich, Jonathan D Rohrer, Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sánchez-Valle (* equivalent contribution).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification between early onset Alzheimer´s disease and frontotemporal dementia using a single neuroimaging feature</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-etaiml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-etaiml/</guid>
      <description>Agnès Pérez Millan, Laia Borrell, José Contador, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch. Emerging Topics in Artificial Intelligence (ETAI) 2022.
ABSTRACT
INTRODUCTION: Early Onset Alzheimer’s Disease (EOAD, &amp;lt;65 years) and Frontotemporal Dementia (FTD) are common forms of early-onset dementia. Therefore, there is a need to establish accurate diagnosis and to obtain markers for disease tracking. We combined supervised and unsupervised machine learning (ML) to discriminate between EOAD and FTD patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Topics in Artificial Intelligence (ETAI) 2022</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-etai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-etai/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Laia Borrell,José Contador,Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch.
TITLE: Classification between Early Onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and frontotemporal dementia using a single neuroimaging feature.
CONFERENCE: Emerging Topics in Artificial Intelligence (ETAI) 2022
PLACE: San Diego, Unitated States of America
DATES: August 21 - 25, 2022
ABSTRACT:
INTRODUCTION: Early Onset Alzheimer’s Disease (EOAD) and Frontotemporal Dementia (FTD) are common forms of early-onset dementia. Therefore, there is a need to establish accurate diagnosis and to obtain markers for disease tracking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential Gene Expression in Sporadic and Genetic Forms of Alzheimer’s Disease and Frontotemporal Dementia in Brain Tissue and Lymphoblastoid Cell Lines</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-gens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-gens/</guid>
      <description>Oscar Ramos-Campoy, Albert Lladó, Beatriz Bosch, Mireia Ferrer, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Miguel Vergara, Laura Molina-Porcel, Laura Fort-Aznar, Ricardo Gonzalo, Fermín Moreno-Izco, Guadalupe Fernandez-Villullas, Mircea Balasa, Raquel Sánchez-Valle, Anna Antonell. Molecular Neurobiology.
ABSTRACT
Sporadic early-onset Alzheimer’s disease (EOAD) and autosomal dominant Alzheimer’s disease (ADAD) provide the opportunity to investigate the physiopathological mechanisms in the absence of aging, present in late-onset forms. Frontotemporal dementia (FTD) causes early-onset dementia associated to tau or TDP43 protein deposits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OHBM 2022 ANNUAL MEETING</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-ohbmapm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-ohbmapm/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, José Contador, Neus Falgàs, Núria Bargalló, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch.
TITLE: Prognosis of Alzheimer’s Disease and Frontotemporal Dementia with a brain age model.
CONFERENCE: OHBM 2022 ANNUAL MEETING
PLACE: Glasgow, United Kingdom
DATES: June 19 - 23, 2022
ABSTRACT:
Introduction: Alzheimer Disease (AD) and Frontotemporal Dementia (FTD) are common forms of dementia, characterized by progressive brain atrophy at variable rates along the age continuum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OHBM 2022 ANNUAL MEETING</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-ohbmut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-ohbmut/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Uma Maria Lal-Trehan Estrada, Agnès Pérez-Millan, José Contador, Neus Falgàs, Núria Bargalló, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch.
TITLE: Indices of cortical asymmetry in Alzheimer’s Disease and Frontotemporal Dementia.
CONFERENCE: OHBM 2022 ANNUAL MEETING
PLACE: Glasgow, United Kingdom
DATES: June 19 - 23, 2022
ABSTRACT:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AD/PD 2022 International Conference on Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s Diseases</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-adpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-adpd/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, José Contador, Neus Falgàs, Núria Bargalló, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez- Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch
TITLE: Using age-matched templates to depict patterns of atrophy in AD and FTD.
CONFERENCE: AD/PD 2022 International Conference on Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s Diseases
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: March 15 - 20, 2022
ABSTRACT:
OBJECTIVES: Alzheimer Disease (AD) and Frontotemporal Dementia (FTD) are characterized by progressive brain atrophy at variable rates along the age continuum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jornada STEM: visibilitzem l’enginyeria</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-youngitgirls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-youngitgirls/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Laia Borrell, José Contador, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch.
TITLE: Classificació entre la malaltia d’Alzheimer i la demència frontotemporal mitjançant una única característica de neuroimatge.
CONFERENCE: Jornada STEM: visibilitzem l’enginyeria
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: February 1, 2022</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Annual Meeting of the ISMRM Iberian Chapter</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2021-isrm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2021-isrm/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Laia Borrell, José Contador, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch.
TITLE: Classification between Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal dementia using a single neuroimaging feature.
CONFERENCE: 2021 Annual Meeting of the ISMRM Iberian Chapter
PLACE: Virtual Event
DATES: June 16 - 17, 2021
ABSTRACT:
INTRODUCTION: Alzheimer Disease (AD) and Frontotemporal Dementia (FTD) are common forms of early-onset dementia with different, but partly overlapping, symptoms and brain signatures. There is a need to establish accurate diagnosis and to obtain good markers for prognosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribution of CSF biomarkers to early-onset Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal dementia neuroimaging signatures</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2020-ohbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2020-ohbm/</guid>
      <description>Neus Falgàs, Mariona Ruiz‐Peris, Agnès Pérez‐Millan, Roser Sala‐Llonch, Anna Antonell, Mircea Balasa, Sergi Borrego‐Écija, Oscar Ramos‐Campoy, Josep Maria Augé, Magdalena Castellví, Adrià Tort‐Merino, Jaume Olives, Guadalupe Fernández‐Villullas, Kaj Blennow, Henrik Zetterberg, Núria Bargalló, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sánchez‐Valle. Human Brain Mapping.
ABSTRACT
Prior studies have described distinct patterns of brain gray matter and white matter alterations in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease (AD) and frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD), as well as differences in their cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) biomarkers profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
