<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neuropathology on Agnès Pérez-Millan</title>
    <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/neuropathology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neuropathology on Agnès Pérez-Millan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/neuropathology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Increase in wasteosomes (corpora amylacea) in frontotemporal lobar degeneration with specific detection of tau, TDP-43 and FUS pathology</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-watesomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-watesomes/</guid>
      <description>Raquel Alsina, Marta Riba, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Iban Aldecoa, Clara Romera, Mircea Balasa, Anna Antonell, Albert Lladó, Yaroslau Compta, Jaume Del Valle, Raquel Sánchez-Valle, Carme Pelegrí, Laura Molina-Porcel, Jordi Vilaplana. Acta Neuropathologica Communications
ABSTRACT
Wasteosomes (or corpora amylacea) are polyglucosan bodies that appear in the human brain with aging and in some neurodegenerative diseases, and have been suggested to have a potential role in a nervous system cleaning mechanism. Despite previous studies in several neurodegenerative disorders, their status in frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD) remains unexplored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galectin-3 is upregulated in frontotemporal dementia patients with subtype specificity</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-gal3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-gal3/</guid>
      <description>Sergi Borrego-Écija*, Agnès Pérez-Millan*, Anna Antonell, Laura Fort-Aznar, Elif Kaya-Tilki, Alberto León-Halcón, Albert Lladó, Laura Molina-Porcel, Mircea Balasa, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Javier Vitorica, Jose Luis Venero, Tomas Deierborg, Antonio Boza-Serrano, Raquel Sánchez-Valle. (* equivalent contribution). Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; Dementia.
ABSTRACT
INTRODUCTION Neuroinflammation is a major contributor to the progression of frontotemporal dementia (FTD). Galectin-3 (Gal-3), a microglial activation regulator, holds promise as a therapeutic target and potential biomarker. Our study aimed to investigate Gal-3 levels in patients with FTD and assess its diagnostic potential.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
