<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plasma on Agnès Pérez-Millan</title>
    <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/plasma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plasma on Agnès Pérez-Millan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/plasma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>XXVIII Reunió Anual Societat Catalana de Neurologia</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-catalana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-catalana/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Neus Falgàs, Beatriz Bosch, Uma Maria Lal-Trehan Estrada, Núria Guillén, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sánchez-Valle
TITLE: Asimetria cortical en individus en risc de patir malaltia d&amp;rsquo;Alzheimer
CONFERENCE: XXVIII Reunió Anual Societat Catalana de Neurologia
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: May 8 - 10, 2024</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Down Syndrome associated Alzheimer disease (DSAD) and autosomal dominant AD (ADAD)</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-adad-rsv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2024-adad-rsv/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Neus Falgàs, Beatriz Bosch, Uma Maria Lal-Trehan Estrada, Núria Guillén, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sánchez-Valle
TITLE: Cortical Asymmetry in individuals with Autosomal Dominant Alzheimer’s Disease
CONFERENCE: Down Syndrome associated Alzheimer disease (DSAD) and autosomal dominant AD (ADAD)
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: April 11 - 12, 2024</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of demographics and comorbid conditions on plasma biomarkers concentrations and their diagnostic accuracy in a memory clinic cohort</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-plasma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-plasma/</guid>
      <description>Jordi Sarto, Diana Esteller-Gauxax, Adrià Tort-Merino, Núria Guillén, Agnès Pérez‐Millan, Neus Falgàs, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Guadalupe Fernández-Villullas, Beatriz Bosch, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Anna Antonell, Laura Naranjo, Raquel Ruiz-García, Josep María Augé, Raquel Sánchez-Valle, Albert Lladó, Mircea Balasa. Journal of Neurology.
ABSTRACT
Plasma biomarkers have emerged as promising tools for identifying amyloid beta (Aβ) pathology. Before implementation in routine clinical practice, confounding factors modifying their concentration beyond neurodegenerative diseases should be identified. We studied the association of a comprehensive list of demographics, comorbidities, medication and laboratory parameters with plasma p-tau181, glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) and neurofilament light chain (NfL) on a prospective memory clinic cohort and studied their impact on diagnostic accuracy for discriminating CSF/amyloid PET-defined Aβ status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galectin-3 is upregulated in frontotemporal dementia patients with subtype specificity</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-gal3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-gal3/</guid>
      <description>Sergi Borrego-Écija*, Agnès Pérez-Millan*, Anna Antonell, Laura Fort-Aznar, Elif Kaya-Tilki, Alberto León-Halcón, Albert Lladó, Laura Molina-Porcel, Mircea Balasa, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Javier Vitorica, Jose Luis Venero, Tomas Deierborg, Antonio Boza-Serrano, Raquel Sánchez-Valle. (* equivalent contribution). Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; Dementia.
ABSTRACT
INTRODUCTION Neuroinflammation is a major contributor to the progression of frontotemporal dementia (FTD). Galectin-3 (Gal-3), a microglial activation regulator, holds promise as a therapeutic target and potential biomarker. Our study aimed to investigate Gal-3 levels in patients with FTD and assess its diagnostic potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAIC 2023</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaicsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaicsb/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Sergi Borrego Écija, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Raquel Ruiz-García, Jordi Sarto, Neus Falgàs, Diana Esteller, Núria Guillén, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Guadalupe Fernández, Yolanda González, Adrià Tort-Merino, Bea Bosch, Laura Fort-Aznar, Anna Antonell, Laura Naranjo, Albert Lladó, Mircea Balasa, Raquel Sanchez-Valle.
TITLE: Plasma Nfl predicts neuroimaging alterations and functional decline in frontotemporal dementia.
CONFERENCE: Alzheimer’s Association International Conference (AAIC) 2023
PLACE: Amsterdam, Netherlands
DATES: July 16 - 20, 2023</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
