<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neuropsychology on Agnès Pérez-Millan</title>
    <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/neuropsychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neuropsychology on Agnès Pérez-Millan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/neuropsychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive profile, neuroimaging and fluid biomarkers in post-acute COVID-19 syndrome</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2024-covid/</guid>
      <description>Núria Guillén*, Agnès Pérez-Millan*, Neus Falgàs, Gema M Lledó-Ibáñez, Lorena Rami, Jordi Sarto, Maria A Botí, Cristina Arnaldos-Pérez, Raquel Ruiz-García, Laura Naranjo, Bàrbara Segura, Mircea Balasa, Roser Sala-Llonch, Albert Lladó, Sarah M Gray, Jason K Johannesen, Madeline M Pantoni, Grant A Rutledge, Ruta Sawant, Yi Wang, Luke S Watson, Josep Dalmau, Raquel Sánchez‐Valle. (* equivalent contribution). Scientific Reports.
ABSTRACT
We aimed to characterize the cognitive profile of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome (PACS) patients with cognitive complaints, exploring the influence of biological and psychological factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAIC 2023</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaiccovid-apm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaiccovid-apm/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Agnès Pérez-Millan, Núria Guillén, Neus Falgàs, María Ángeles Botí, Adrià Tort-Merino, Gema María Lledó-Ibáñez, Raquel Ruiz-García, Laura Naranjo, Lorena Rami, Mircea Balasa, Albert Lladó, Roser Sala-Llonch, Raquel Sanchez-Valle.
TITLE: Exploring the relationship between MRI changes and cognitive/neuropsychiatric complaints in a cohort of long COVID-19 patients: A cross-sectional and longitudinal study.
CONFERENCE: Alzheimer’s Association International Conference (AAIC) 2023
PLACE: Amsterdam, Netherlands
DATES: July 16 - 20, 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAIC 2023</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaiccovid-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2023-aaiccovid-ng/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: Núria Guillén, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Neus Falgàs, María Ángeles Botí, Adrià Tort-Merino, Gema María Lledó-Ibáñez, Raquel Ruiz-García, Laura Naranjo, Lorena Rami, Mircea Balasa, Roser Sala-Llonch, Albert Lladó, Raquel Sanchez-Valle.
TITLE: Cognitive symptoms associated with COVID-19: neuropsychological and biochemical characterization.
CONFERENCE: Alzheimer’s Association International Conference (AAIC) 2023
PLACE: Amsterdam, Netherlands
DATES: July 16 - 20, 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and validation of the 1-week memory battery for assessing episodic memory and accelerated long-term forgetting in cognitively unimpaired subjects.</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2023-neuropsico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2023-neuropsico/</guid>
      <description>Lorena Rami, María León, Natalia Valech, Nina Coll-Padrós, Beatriz Bosch, Jaume Olives, Ana Salinero, Agnès Pérez-Millan, José Luis Molinuevo, Raquel Sánchez-Valle, Adrià Tort-Merino. Neuropsychology.
ABSTRACT
Objective: Subtle decline in memory is thought to arise in the preclinical phase of Alzheimer’s disease (AD). However, detecting these initial cognitive difficulties cross-sectionally has been challenging, and the exact nature of the decline is still debated. Accelerated long-term forgetting (ALF) has been recently suggested as one of the earliest and most sensitive indicators of memory dysfunction in subjects at risk of developing AD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
