<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sex Differences on Agnès Pérez-Millan</title>
    <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/sex-differences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sex Differences on Agnès Pérez-Millan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Agnes2.github.io/tags/sex-differences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sex differences in early-onset Alzheimer’s disease</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/publications/2022-sex/</guid>
      <description>José Contador*, Agnès Pérez-Millan*, Nuria Guillen, Jordi Sarto, Adrià Tort-Merino, Mircea Balasa, Neus Falgàs, Magdalena Castellví, Sergi Borrego-Écija, Jordi Juncà-Parella, Beatriz Bosch, Guadalupe Fernández-Villullas, Oscar Ramos-Campoy, Anna Antonell, Nuria Bargalló, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala Llonch, Albert Lladó (* equivalent contribution). European Journal of Neurology.
ABSTRACT
INTRODUCTION: Sex is believed to drive heterogeneity in Alzheimer’s disease (AD), although evidence in early-onset AD (&amp;lt;65 years, EOAD) is scarce.
METHODS: We included 62 EOAD patients and 44 healthy controls (HC) with cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) AD’s core biomarkers and neurofilament light chain levels, neuropsychological assessment, and 3T-MRI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AD/PD 2022 International Conference on Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s Diseases</title>
      <link>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-adpdjc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Agnes2.github.io/conferences/2022-adpdjc/</guid>
      <description>AUTHORS: José Contador, Agnès Pérez-Millan, Nuria Guillen, Jordi Sarto, Adrià Tort-Merino, Jordi Juncà, Mircea Balasa, Neus Falgàs, Magdalena Castellví, Beatriz Bosch, Guadalupe Fernández-Villullas, Oscar Ramos-Campoy, Anna Antonell, Nuria Bargalló, Raquel Sanchez-Valle, Roser Sala-Llonch, Albert Lladó.
TITLE: Sex Differences in Biomarkers and cognitive profile in early-onset Alzheimer’s disease.
CONFERENCE: AD/PD 2022 International Conference on Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s Diseases
PLACE: Barcelona, Spain
DATES: March 15 - 20, 2022</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
